Let's consider a simple vending machine where everything costs 20 cents.
すべての価格が 20 セントの自動販売機を考えてみましょう
And let's say that this vending machine only takes
この自動販売機は 5 セント貨と 10 セント貨のみ受け付け
nickels and dimes but nothing larger or smaller.
それより大きくても小さくてもダメです
Then we can model the state of
そしてこの自動販売機の状態は 投入された
this vending machine by the amount of money that's been deposited.
お金の額によってモデル化できます
The start state would be zero cents.
開始状態は 0 セントでしょう
And from this date there are two things that can happen.
この状態から 2 つのことが起こり得ます
We could put in a nickel,
5 セント貨を入れて
which would make the state five cents or we
状態を 5 セントにするか 10 セント貨を入れて
could put in a dime to take the state to 10 cents.
状態を 10 セントにするかです
The rest of the transitions are fairly straightforward until we think about
残りの遷移がかなり簡単なのは 15 セントの状態で誰かが
what to do if we are in the 15 cent state and someone puts in a dime.
10 セント貨を入れたらどうするかについて考えるまでです
We could just count that as 20.
それを単に 20 と数えることもできます
But let's say that this machine requires exact change so that
でもこの販売機はちょうどの代金がいるとしましょう
a dime would just fall through and come
そこで 10 セント貨が落ちて 販売機下部の
out of the little tray at the bottom of the machine.
小さいトレイから出てくるようにします
As you can see, finite state machines are pretty straightforward conceptually.
おわかりのように 有限状態機械は概念的に非常に簡単です
So why talk about them?
ではなぜこの話をするのでしょう
They have their strengths and weaknesses.
これらには長所と短所があります
Let's start with our strengths.
長所から見ていきましょう
First, finite state machines are very easy to reason about.
まず 有限状態機械は推論するのが非常に簡単です
They are basically self-documenting because they map
これらは基本的に自己文書的です
the logical state of a system directly to the physical state.
システムの論理状態を物理状態に直接マッピングするからです
When a nickel goes into the vending machine
5 セント貨が自動販売機に入ると
the state changes to the state that is five cents bigger than the current one.
状態は現在よりも 5 セント多くなる状態に変わります
Next, they are maintainable.
次に メンテナンス可能です
If we wanted to tweak this machine so that everything costs
この販売機を手直しして すべての価格が 25 セントになるようにする場合
a quarter it would be pretty trivial to just add one more state.
状態をもう 1 つだけ追加するのは大したことではありません
Which brings us to the weaknesses of the finite state machine.
これは 有限状態機械の短所につながります
The primary one being that they are easily abused.
主な短所は 簡単に悪用されてしまうことです
If they aren't designed well to begin with or if the problem
うまく開始するように設計されていない
changes you can easily find yourself saying things like,
または問題が変わった場合
I hadn't considered that.
このように思うことが簡単に出てきます 「考えていなかった
Let's just add another state and this can lead to some sloppy code and sloppy logic.
別の状態を追加してみよう 」こういったことがいい加減なコードとロジックにつながります
Which in practice means that finite state machines can be
つまり実際 有限状態機械は 状態ベースが大きくなっていくにつれ
very difficult to maintain as the states base gets bigger.
維持が非常に難しくなる場合があることを意味しています